Finding Aid for St. Mark's Episcopal Church (Detroit, Mich.: 1927-) Records, 1927-1994
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
St. Mark's Episcopal Church (Detroit, Mich.: 1927-) Records 1927-1994
St. Mark's Episcopal Church (Detroit, Mich.: 1927-)
4 linear ft. and 1 oversize volume
0248 Ba 2
Episcopal church located in the Seven Mile-Gratiot area of Detroit. Registers of baptisms, confirmations, marriages, burials, etc.; registers of church services; vestry minute books; records of church organizations; historical information; subject files; and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records of the church were donated by the Episcopal Church, Diocese of Michigan (donor no. 1059 ) in 2002.
The record group is open to research.
Episcopal church located in the Seven Mile-Gratiot area of Detroit founded in 1927.
Registers of baptisms, confirmations, marriages, burials, etc.; registers of church services; vestry minute books; records of church organizations; historical information; subject files; and photographs.
Subjects:
St. Mark's Episcopal Church (Detroit, Mich.: 1927-); Registers of births, etc.--Michigan--Detroit.; Detroit (Mich.)--Church history.; Episcopal Church--Michigan--Detroit.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- History and Background
  - Historical sketches (Box 1)
  - Anniversary program and other informational publications (Box 1)
  - Membership directories and various other lists, 1 folder and 21 volumes (Box 1)
  - Program: Dedication of St. Mark's Church, June 14, 1953 (Box 1)
  - First meeting and charter members, November 4, 1927 (Box 1)
  - Request and dialog concerning admission of St. Mark's to parish status, 1943 (Box 1)
- Vestry Minutes 1927-1952
  - 1927-1928 (Box 1)
  - 1936-1941 (Box 1)
  - 1941-1943 (Box 1)
  - Volume I, 1943-1953 (Box 1)
  - Volume II, 1953-1959 (Box 1)
  - Volume III, 1960-1965 (Box 1)
  - Volume IV, 1966-1985 (Box 2)
  - Volume V, 1985-1994 (Box 2)
  - Communications to the Vestry, 1943-1952 (Box 2)
- Church Organizations
  - Minute book, League of Women of St. Mark's Episcopal Church, 1927-1930 (Box 2)
  - Minutes of St. Mark's Episcopal Churchwomen, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Record book, Men of St. Marks, 1959-1969 (Box 2)
  - Mary Herron Guild miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Church School Teacher's record book, 1936-1946 (Box 2)
  - Parish organization reports, 1951 (Box 2)
- Registers of Baptisms, marriages, confirmations; burials
  - Combined record book: Baptisms, 1928-1949 Confirmations, 1928-1945 Burials, 1928-1955 Marriages, 1928-1954 (Box 3)
    (oversize volume)
  - Confirmations, 1946-1993 (Box 3)
  - Marriages, 1955-1993 (Box 3)
    - Marriages, 1955-1974 (Box 3)
    - Marriages, 1974-1987 (Box 3)
    - Marriages, 1987-1993 (Box 3)
  - Communicants, 1946-1997 (Box 3)
    - Communicants, 1946-1963 (Box 3)
    - Communicants, 1964-1997 (Box 3)
  - Baptisms, 1949-1997 (Box 3)
    - Baptisms, 1949-1977 (Box 3)
    - Baptisms, 1977-1997 (Box 3)
  - Burials, 1955-1994 (Box 3)
  - Burial miscellaneous (Box 3)
- Register of Church Services, 1927-2001
  - 1927-1944 (Box 4)
  - 1945-1954 (Box 4)
  - 1955-1962 (Box 4)
  - 1962-1965 (Box 4)
  - 1965-1972 (Box 4)
  - 1972-1978 (Box 4)
  - 1979-1986 (Box 4)
  - 1987-2001 (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous annual reports, 1955-1960 (Box 4)
  - Financial Reports, 1940-1965
    - Financial Reports, 1960-1965 (Box 4)
    - Financial Reports, 1940-1952 (Box 4)
  - Minutes of St. Marks Bldg. Committee, 1945-1953 (Box 4)
  - Church school meetings, 1947-1961 (scattered) (Box 4)
  - Photographs (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4)